<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on Dinesh Pai's blog</title><link>https://dineshpai.in/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on Dinesh Pai's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dineshpai.in/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Venture Capital demands from budget 2024</title><link>https://dineshpai.in/blog/venture-world-and-budget-day/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dineshpai.in/blog/venture-world-and-budget-day/</guid><description>TL;DR Momentum in the Indian startup ecosystem can be sustained with a few tweaks to taxation and adding more infrastructure resources. Angel Tax should be relaxed and viewed from the domestic capital formation angle lens. ESOP taxation must be simplified and some relaxation for folks who lose out due to dual taxation. Capital gains on private investments could be simplified and rationalised to be similar to public investments - at 10% instead of the current 20%.</description></item><item><title>Venture Capital for 2024 and beyond</title><link>https://dineshpai.in/blog/venture-capital-for-2024-and-beyond/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dineshpai.in/blog/venture-capital-for-2024-and-beyond/</guid><description>TL;DR The reset of the ecosystem from a funding standpoint will only mean India will emerge stronger and better from a private investments standpoint. Education, healthcare, and financial services will be the sectors that will be disrupted over the next few years and will add value to India&amp;rsquo;s growth story. Aspirations across the Indian population (both urban and rural) are the same. And we should move past India 1,2,3 segregation (based on per capita income) For Rainmatter, the longevity of businesses we support is critical.</description></item><item><title>Lessons, learnings and gratitude - 2023</title><link>https://dineshpai.in/blog/lessons-learnings-and-gratitude-2023/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dineshpai.in/blog/lessons-learnings-and-gratitude-2023/</guid><description>Back in January of this year, I promised myself to write as much as possible this year. Naturally, I clasped at every opportunity to write and share my thoughts on almost everything - personal and professional. And while we are wrapping up this year, it’s only fitting that I end the year with a blog.
In this piece, I share most of the things I have learned and picked up this year.</description></item><item><title>Musings on the venture world for 2024</title><link>https://dineshpai.in/blog/musings-on-the-cashflow-conundrum-in-the-venture-world/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dineshpai.in/blog/musings-on-the-cashflow-conundrum-in-the-venture-world/</guid><description>For the past few months in India, VC investors have started speaking of profitability. Makes no sense, though. The entire VC model is built on VCs subsidising early losses so that the company can eventually capture a significant market share and be sustainable financially. Why are we speaking of this now and now for all this while? We have had two years of crazy valuations and funding rounds, yet we are only being made privy to this elixir of business building now.</description></item><item><title>Bootstrapping in vogue</title><link>https://dineshpai.in/blog/bootstrapping-in-vogue/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dineshpai.in/blog/bootstrapping-in-vogue/</guid><description>India, with the third largest startup ecosystem in the world, has been one of the hotbeds of startup activity over the past few years. We have nearly a million registered startups, increasing 200x since 2016, adding around 9 Lakh direct job opportunities since 2017. The past two years, 2021 and 2022, have attracted almost 60 billion USD in venture capital funding. Compare that with the 8-year period between 2012 and 2020, when just 50 billion USD was invested in Indian startups.</description></item><item><title>The cricket world cup is back in town</title><link>https://dineshpai.in/blog/cricket-world-cup-is-back-in-town/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dineshpai.in/blog/cricket-world-cup-is-back-in-town/</guid><description>The last time the Cricket World Cup came to India was in 2011 - the first year of my engineering degree. Those memories are still vivid, and they all came rushing back a few weeks ago during a meeting attended by several IIT alumni. While they were reminiscing about their college days, my mind kept drifting back to how the CWC was one of the highlights of my college life. Here&amp;rsquo;s an image of us watching a group stage match:</description></item><item><title>Moving on from the funding winter narrative</title><link>https://dineshpai.in/blog/moving-on-from-the-funding-winter-narrative/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dineshpai.in/blog/moving-on-from-the-funding-winter-narrative/</guid><description>Earlier this weekend, I was at the HSX Headstart Summit and was asked a few questions about the startup ecosystem prevalent in India. Headstart is an annual event that aims to bring together entrepreneurs from various parts of the country to share stories and interact with each other. It was amazing to meet several startups from non-metro cities, who were all working on building excellent companies. Undoubtedly, this will help us do better as a country and an economy, having more entrepreneurs build localised solutions for various parts of the country.</description></item><item><title>Venture Capital: 2023 and beyond</title><link>https://dineshpai.in/blog/venture-capital-in-2023-and-what-lies-ahead/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dineshpai.in/blog/venture-capital-in-2023-and-what-lies-ahead/</guid><description>Three decades after the first Venture Capital (VC) firm mushroomed in the US, in 1975, risk capital found its way to India. Even though there were several instances of accidental VC underwriting businesses before 1975, the first formal VC scheme in India was through Industrial Finance Corporation of India (IFCI) interest-free loans. It then took another decade and a half before ICICI and UTI came together to launch a formal Venture Capital Scheme in 1988.</description></item></channel></rss>