<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>investments on Dinesh Pai's blog</title><link>https://dineshpai.in/tags/investments/</link><description>Recent content in investments on Dinesh Pai's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dineshpai.in/tags/investments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Timing and Capital - What your spreadsheets can't tell you</title><link>https://dineshpai.in/blog/timing-and-capital-what-your-spreadsheets-cant-tell-you/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dineshpai.in/blog/timing-and-capital-what-your-spreadsheets-cant-tell-you/</guid><description>Two things about Venture Capital nobody talks about enough Venture capital looks magical from the outside. Billion-dollar exits. Founder stories splashed across the media. Returns that make public markets look boring. But finding these outliers early? It&amp;rsquo;s like finding a needle in a haystack. As Nithin often says, and he&amp;rsquo;s right.
Ask any seasoned investor what makes a good venture bet, and you&amp;rsquo;ll hear the usual suspects. Massive market size, exceptional team, innovative product, fanatical customer love, and defensible moats.</description></item><item><title>Thank you, Mr. Trump</title><link>https://dineshpai.in/blog/tariff-tantrum/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dineshpai.in/blog/tariff-tantrum/</guid><description>Thanks to the United States of America and the current economic dealings with the West, I think we have all had a sudden awakening to the criticality of sovereignty in trade, technology, and intellectual property, especially driven by tariffs. While this is not a brand-new concern, the Indian government has been communicating its importance for years. The difference now is urgency. Although we have some head start and momentum, we are still far from prepared for what lies ahead.</description></item></channel></rss>